Kyle Haugen

2031 I St, Sacramento, California 95811 (916) 337-4286 devkdhaugen@gmail.com

WEB LINKS

Personal Website: https://KDHaugen.github.io/

Github: https://github.com/KDHaugen

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/dev-kyle-haugen/

PROFESSIONAL HISTORY

Dec. 2021 – Present Portland, Oregon

Instructor, The Tech Academy

- Teach students from around the globe in Computer Science materials such as HTML, CSS, Javascript, C#, SQL, Python, Agile and more.
- Help students with their coding assignments using screenshare.

Mar. 2020 - Present

GML2 coder | Mechanical Design | Project Leader, Seeds of Aether

- Created playable video game characters for Seeds of Aether computer game.
- Self taught Game Maker Language 2.0.
- Coordinated project assignments between team mates to complete projects of quality and in a timely manner.
- Communicated with user base to make product as appealing as possible.

Jan. 2021 – Dec. 2021 Portland, Oregon

Software Developer, The Tech Academy

- Developed web applications using HTML, Javascript, CSS and C#.
- Participated in Agility sprints, completing stories and attending daily stand up meetings.

SKILLS

Javascript

MVC Entity

Project Management

Game Maker Language 2.0	
SQL Data Management	
HTML	
Concept Design	
.Net and C#	

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Mathematically educated and creative mind. Driven to create novel and captivating user experiences. Self taught coding during the 2020 pandemic and then pursued education and certification through The Tech Academy boot camp program. Works well in tandem with others and willing to lead. Has an unending thirst to learn and improve.

EDUCATION

Jul. 2021	Computer Science
	The Tech Academy - Portland, Oregon
Dec. 2020	Bachelor of Science: Mathematics
	Sacramento State University of California - Sacramento, California
Jun. 2014	Associate of Science: Psychology
	Folsom Lake College - Folsom, California